Hello, and welcome to one more exciting
session at Conf42 AI Agent 2026.
I'm Dmytro Khlatenko, so I have a very
special talk about a few because one of
its previ- previous versions, they have
been at past editions at Conf42, and
this is a new upgraded versions where I
would take you to the story how the spe-
very specific problem strike together
with AWS knowledge, how I changed the
classic serverless pipeline with agents
and how it influenced the whole workflow.
So f- you are very welcome.
Le- and before I begin with the technical
things, with the introduction of myself,
I would like to bring you to the root
of the story, because this is why I
want to quote here the Steve Jobs that,
"Technology alone is not enough. Married
with the liberal arts, it yields the
results that make our hearts sing."
And this is exactly the case why this talk
exists, why this technical implementation
was created, why this project was
so alive because we have so many
different people in our AWS community.
Some of the people, they are
doing different articles.
People are doing talks at conferences
like that, on online events, at
community days, at the user group.
Some people create tooling,
like for instance Anton Babienko
creates Terraform stuffs.
Other people create Lambda stuff.
And the most important,
the people bring passion.
Passion something outside the h-this
core cloud technical knowledge they
express, they bring to the community,
but they also bring a piece of
themselves, which is important.
And for me, this is a case that I brought
photography together with myself because I
grown up surrounded with the photographers
in the photo lab that my parents owned.
And basically, I have experience
shooting weddings different
events, so many different stuff.
And this leaded me to my place in AWS
community, where I was capturing AWS
Community Day Dark in 2024, and I took
care of the event with s- over 650 amazing
attendees with 30 top-notch speakers.
Also, maybe you can recognize a few
from the picture that, A- and in general
so it was 8,000 pictures that I took
on my own with those two hands, with
my two Sony Alpha cameras, and I was
battling the three main enemies of
every photographer: auto-focus, closed
eyes, and technically wrong pictures.
And to-today, let's go through together
through the story, actually why it
was created, how the first approach,
which was completely serverless-based.
Let's speak how agents are changing
the workflows in such in cases,
and let's speak about the whole
organizational and usability part.
Also I am taking pictures, different ones.
So I'm taking pictures
of Formula 1 for my blog.
I take part in different moto days,
in the different mo- track days, wha-
whatever happening around in the region.
So in AWS community, I'm pretty known,
especially in the Europe, because I'm
taking care of community events pretty…
When I have capacity, I'm supporting
documentally our AWS user group in Vienna.
Maybe you have even seen some
of the pictures that I took on
LinkedIn of some famous speakers.
And also this is a missing slide because
the slide deck from Summit Zurich.
And I also to work with
the professional models.
I had the honor to work with
the pho- models from Playboy.
I am part of European Venice
different exhibitions for both
analog and digital photography
and yeah, I'm Dmytro Khlatenko.
I'm AWS community builder,
AWS user group leader EVN.
I'm senior cloud operations
engineer in Sage.
So in Sage we develop HR, ERP CRM,
different solutions for different
businesses worldwide, and I'm honored to
take care of the Sage DPW, our flagship
product for the Austrian market that
calculates the salary for the lots
of ma- major businesses in Austria.
I'm motorsport fan.
I love everything tech
related, science related.
I like a lot of things that
have a lot of life in that.
And I also have six AWS certifications,
master in telecommunication.
So I have bachelor in business management.
And let's have a look how the--
my creation actually influenced
the community, and because on this
particular event, it allowed to
quickly scale down to 8,000 picture to
a selection signature deck of 1,249.
It wa- we were able to keep the
pulse of all this shared commitment
of community day and have a good
marketing coverage that year.
And then the same solution went to five
different events, five additional talks,
even I would already say seven and, This
is the eighth, and the solution keeps
going, running steady since its creation
in 2024 and constantly being improved.
So I have a lot of motivation
to keep doing the pictures.
First of all, it's for speakers because
so much of the effort actually comes
to take, make a talk, to make, take
a good case that you can present some
community commitment, articles, videos.
It's really deserves a lot of time that
people take away from their beloved
ones, kids, families, free time.
And this my target why I do that,
to support them to have a better
visibility for the work they are doing.
Also for the sponsors, because it
takes a lot of communication from
our side to take and secure the
sponsorship for the such kind of events.
And then it's good to bring a good
respectable representation of the
sponsorship commitment for the companies.
It's for us to-- for me because
I'm very sentimental to the things.
I like to go back through the old
album, albums and see some past
things that happened in my life.
And also it's something that
I like to revisit and see, oh,
how great was the line in 2024.
And also, so you know the thing when
you have a friend who is at your camera
and they took a picture, it's not
about taking a pictures, it's actually
pro- to process and sort out the bad
pictures because they are battling
bad focus despite modern mirrorless
have superior autofocus systems.
And it leads to another issue
this solution was also solving.
We fighting with the closed eyes, bad
face expressions, and we have to analyze
every single picture not only from the
view, like presentation of it, but also
from the technical part like bad exposure.
And in general, when we are pr- preparing
the community day, we are thinking
actually of what kind of content we
might need at which point of time.
We know our posts, we know our content,
we know that at that time we would need
such pictures, and this is something then
that transitions in the second phase.
When I'm taking actually the cameras,
taking the pictures, and here I can only
control the damage, but it will still
result in the big work on the third stage.
And this is something where I applied my
work approach that I'm trying to analyze
the and see how I'm doing the things,
because usually it's a huge manual work.
First of all, to take out the meaningful
selection of the pictures that would
cover the emotions and they would not be
so repeatable, but also to technically
process because we have different
lightning, different situations.
Also maybe to apply some creativity
and then the delivery Which is
actually not an issue in comparison.
The third stage, and this project, it
leaded to the full automation using
serverless logic on AWS that I was
taking a picture, it was landing to
S3 bucket, it was triggering a cascade
of different serverless triggers,
triggering the step functions where
I have had the custom Lambdas that
used to relied on AWS recognition.
Then I… they based on my past event
knowledge, pre- performed the analysis
and mechanical transformations, and then
we were packing them in a different di-
good or bad pictures, which were sorted
by speaker, by event time, by everything.
And this solution allowed me to
scale down days of work just to
40 minutes and some bill on AWS.
But let's not go so that fast.
Actually I really like to think about AWS
like a Swiss Army knife because there is a
good majority of the services, and if you
get familiar, if you get confident with
them for instance, if you're good with
the Lambdas, with the serverless coupling,
if you can know what to do with the
different storage AWS offers, DynamoDB,
you already open up an opportunity.
An opportunity you have
to see it as an engineer.
First of all, I'm trying to understand
what kind of capabilities my team has.
For instance, I know that this colleague
has this information, that information,
and it's a mastery to orchestrate it.
Then I'm thinking what
kind of data do we process?
What does this data represent for
the human and for the machine,
and how it would like on the
different processing stages?
I think what technology offers, not
only for in case of AWS, for instance.
I have very special cases every single day
at work, and I have to rely on everything,
on technology and also on the humans, on
the legal side and on their capabilities.
And it's very important
to know how to get it.
And first of all it was pretty
understandable for me that such an issue
would arise, and I was already in the
mood to take days of work to sort it out.
But it would actually damage
the pools that-- those good
ground that we-- foundation
that we laid down for the event.
So then actually one of the things
came from my… At that time, I
worked at Austrian Press Agency,
amazing place with amazing people,
and I just saw some photographers
that were standing at the entrance.
And basically, I looked at them and
I thought, "Maybe this is the way,"
because photographers, a lot of
professional cameras they have the
FTP transfer function, and I know
Nikon cameras that I used before, Sony
alphas have the inbuilt FTP agent.
And I just came back home and I
started to think which service.
Ah, AWS Transfer Family.
I spin up a public endpoint.
I created the certificate, loaded the
certificate on the camera, connected
my camera to Wi- Wi-Fi network.
Then I clicked the button, I held the
breath, then I saw the blinking indication
that file was actually uploaded.
I went to AWS console, opened S3 bucket,
saw the pictures here, and this is the
feeling when your idea has a perspective.
But then from this stage,
it's important to develop it.
Because then I was pretty much happy
because, okay, we can transfer the files.
We don't need Google Drive.
We don't need some other things, right?
And, I I was thinking okay,
we don't have to mess with the
memory cards and colleagues, they
can just work with the SD card.
It's amazing.
And at that time I was working
to-- for the project for ORF.
We wanted to make a live stream
recognition of the Austrian celebrities
to do the automatical typing.
And for that, we used AWS Rekognition,
which brings a lot of good
opportunities to-- for image processing.
And it was a very crucial and important
part in this story because as it was
popular at the time, it was a ramp-up of
AI, and I thought if I could just give
it to the Claude and not to mess up and
to get too deep in one more service.
And I was lucky because I have had very
good representable datasets and on which
I could actually try out the ideas and
that they would also be representable.
But it was very important
for the next step.
But at that step, I gave a system
prompt to Claude that you are a
photographer for the press agency, and
you have to evaluate if this picture
is good enough for the publishing.
And while Claude was quite successful
with working with the pictures of
the people who doesn't wear glasses,
Claude failed with the glasses.
And where I took the samples of of
my counterpart, Linda Mohamed, AWS
hero, and unfortunately, Claude was
not applicable for this specific case.
And then I thought, okay, let's have a
look what actually AWS Rekognition offers.
And in this case, I got a very important
combination of the data, because
first of all, I got the parameters
from Rekognition that were numerical
representity, which is important.
And also it expressed different physical
parameters of the picture that I'm
evaluating with the cog-cognitively.
So face expression eyes, mouth,
ears, position of the head.
Yeah.
And this is what's crucial
for the visual analysis.
For the technical side,
I have the EXIF data.
In every single picture you are
taking with the camera, you have
EXIF data that includes all the
important technical information.
And I also was lucky because I've
worked many years with the DxO PhotoLab,
and I think it's pretty much the most
superior AI converter on the market.
But what was cool, that for every
single picture I processed, it leaves
the JSON with the parameters, what
kind of actually corrections and what
I applied for a particular feature.
And then it was a question
how to compile it.
I have-- And then I had
two distinct datasets.
The first one, they were complete
library of all picture taken at
different AWS community events.
And then the next stage was about
making the second half of the pictures
that I processed, that I selected,
that I used for the publishing.
And this is-- And out of that, I
generated a Parquet file that was
hot loaded at that time by the Lambda
in the-- from this shared storage.
And it allowed me to form
the golden set of the data.
And then the whole work flew
through the different data approach
that I was taking a picture.
It was coming through the
transfer gateway to the S3 bucket.
S3 bucket was triggering an S3 event
that was going to the SQS with a
DLQ queue for the red drive policy.
Then I had step function, which was
built all the customized Lambdas,
which were used based on Libero to
have an opportunity to work with
the files produced by the camera.
And then I have had the recognition phase.
Then the-- based on the 20
similarity choices, the cloud
was making up the parameters.
Then the picture was developed and
allocated in the selected bucket
for the specific metadata for the
automatic sorting per the event And
in this approach, I first of all, I
replaced my eyes with AWS Rekognition.
My knowledge was represented
into the calibrated thresholds
over the existing datasets.
Then Claude on based on the already
good examples was picking the
parameters, and my development was
basically handled by the Lambdas.
And this solution was pretty cheap.
It was pretty much accurate if you d-
don't take into account the edge cases.
And it wa- it allowed
really to save so much time.
And you could ask me, why do you
actually need to work with the raw here?
So I would answer tell you the
answer because first of all,
it's about the information.
And in the raw file, you have 14 bits
of information, and in, in JPEG it
it's only eight bits of information.
You could ask me like,
what's the difference?
And difference is very huge because me
personally as a speaker, I would be very
annoyed if some guy just flies in front
of me when I'm presenting, focused on my
attendees, going through my slides, and
he starts to fire with a flash in my eyes.
And all these scenes they are very s- hard
actually situations for the camera because
mostly we have a bright background of the
slides, we have a shadow on the speaker,
and we have to have a good dynamic range.
Then we can recover backlights,
highlights, shadows, and have a
very good dynamic range where slides
are visible, person is visible.
And also Libre was very important
to first of all, to take out the
thumbnails, say from the initial
like a mechanical first stage of
pre-processing with the Rekognition.
Then if it's a good
picture, we double-check it.
If it's a burst, we cumulate
of taking the best picture and
an- analyzing the siblings.
And actually, I was thinking a
lot what I would like to use in
this place because I was thinking
about EC2 instances with GPUs.
I was thinking about containers, but
all of these ideas crashed because not
that much of good software is capable
to work for out of the environment.
And Lambdas, I was trying to
scale the performance with the
memory assignment to the Lambda.
But also what was important is that
so It was very crucial and reused
in many p-p-parts of the pipeline.
And the pipeline, it got a very
good feedback from the speakers.
It tr-- it handled four quality events
in the different in this particular
conference season, and many speakers,
they really liked the opportunity.
And I I saw the pictures, a lot of good
words in my direction for this solution.
But there was a big issue.
It was good while it lived in the
conference room, because when I took the
same approach to my Formula One archives,
to the studio archives, to the other
events, it was basically kicking away
all the pictures because it's just not…
The pipeline mechanically doesn't know
that how you can evaluate cars, how
you could evaluate th-this and that.
So-- and it was guessing.
It was guessing because it had
a very limited knowledge on the
particular datasets because scenes,
they are pretty much familiar.
They're only different, not that
much, and this is why Claude was
mixing the actual parameters.
Then there was always a guess that good
pictures might still fly to the archive
bucket and bad pictures could still
arrive to the good bucket, and I haven't
had any f-f-human in the loop feedback.
And this is why, for an example
every parameter that I was having
from the data I showed to you
before, it had different weight, how
it influences the final decision.
And sometimes if picture is good and could
be recovered manually, pipeline didn't
think about it because it's the next
stage before it actually was happening.
And and then for example, this
picture, it was thrown away.
And it was a very big task how to
eliminate those guesses, and this
is why I decided Terraform destroy.
And it worked on all those events.
It was great, and it was collecting dust.
The time was going.
I changed the work.
I cha- broke up with my partner.
I changed the camera.
And it was a great time when I was flying
to Abu Dhabi to ga- give the AWS re:Invent
recap at AWS User Group in Abu Dhabi.
And I was reading about the Strand
agents, and my first idea when on
the plane was, "Oh my God, this
is something that I could apply."
And it leaded to the press agency that
not only closed the three gaps for the
guessing, it closed seven holes because
first of all we have had one-shot calls,
and even with the policy retrying SQS,
it was always one-shot processing without
of different feedback cycles, yeah.
Tools, they were welded in the code and,
you're just like, I don't know, some
Gemini who are, like, two barns together.
And memory, it was frozen ta-taste into
J-JSON, and It was any step could do
anything it wanted and it could collapse.
A very good perspective,
like on the example that I
showed showed for you today.
There was no observability.
I have had only the logs fro-
and some callbacks from the--
that I left for the debug.
And my metrics is it was just my taste.
It was not flexible, and the whole
delivery, it was fully manual.
That's why it got upgraded to this.
And you could get familiar with
the skeleton because the po-
main part, it was not deleted.
It just moved like an entrance because I
wanted to avoid the situation that you buy
Ferrari and you drive around your building
with a twenty kilometers per hour.
And this is not what they are you doing
because say it's important not to overfit
but also underfit, and this was a good
case to pa- take out really bad cases
at the entrance to-- and to use the
agents really for something valuable.
Transfer family, aman breach, SQS,
step functions they're untouched
because it was never wrong.
Wha-what is really new that the
side boxes are now agents that
are running on Bedrock Agent Core.
Look at the flow.
The express line, as you can
see here, it allows us to do
everything fast in milliseconds.
And then we really can do it in
the asynchronous way because I
have time for the picture to be
presented because there is a huge
forty-five-minute slot for the session.
And that's why it was applicable,
we had time to reason.
They call my old lambdas actually
that were converted into the tooling.
I've wrapped recognition, I wrapped
Libero, Exif tool as MCP tools
through the age-- agent core gateway.
They have memory, they get self-improving.
If for instance, if the curator agent
suspec-suspects some edge case, he
commits it to the memory, to the
git, I review it, and then either
I discard or it goes to the memory
and gets self-continuously improved.
So it's like Germes agent, but for the
pictures, and this is simply amazing.
So and everyone was asking "Where are the
weights? How did you remove those bias
created by them?" No, they actually just
got rerouted in the different department.
In the first version, the
weights were the whole decision.
In the version two, they live in the
express line in the step functions.
So yeah, as you, you-- I mentioned before
we were pre-filtering and if those numbers
before they have been verdict, right?
And in the every rejection,
it was a complete silence.
It was just a number, it's
like authoritarian system.
And in the version two,
this number is a testimony.
It's a evidence tool that basically agent
use like a tool, like a light meter,
for instance, if you use a an analog
camera and you need to measure the light.
And we reasoned the context,
the parameters of the
Exif, they self-explanatory
similar frames, craft rules.
It all was all about removing this gap.
When the first version was wrong, the
version two writes a rational episode
log, and then it converts the every
single case into the skill difference.
And remember it like that because the
thresholds decide the volume that go to
the agent, and then agent decides a-about
the doubts on the cases it processes.
And when we speak about the agents, you
would ask me, how did I assemble it?
Let's think about the agent
a-as a six distinct parts.
First of all, we have a model.
Models, I will cover it later because
they have a very important function But
the most important, they are pri- hired
for the job, for the price, because you
don't want to have a senior engineer
on the tech support and for example.
Se- then you have a skill.
I have had two different sources.
I distilled my own craft, and
also I shaped the best practices
that are recognized approaches
by the famous photographers.
They are something that gives the good
visibility for the skill to be fortified
those edge cases, bias, and give a
reasoning foundation for the agent.
Then we have every single tool
through AgentCore gateway.
So my Lambdas, they became the tooling.
Now they are unchanged by--
in the form of the MCP.
Memory, namespace, na-namespaces,
this is what I'm keeping, and
I'm keeping the crucial cases
to get it better and ba-better.
What is boring are the guardrails because
I use standard Bedrock, and this is an
internal tool, so I pretty much confident
with the content that I'm giving to it.
But maybe it is the good
room for improvement.
And the output is simple.
We use it in a different perspective.
For the sourcing, for the da-data
analysis, we use the output to
understand what was actually
the behavior of the agent.
And every verdict is a JSON, but
this is a rational J-JSON, and
every rejection has a motive in the
memory, and it differs between the
five is exactly the three things: the
model, the skill, and the tool set.
And what is important, for
instance, I have now a critic gate.
Critic is blind, and he doesn't operate
with the information that available for
the other agents on the other stage.
So going forward I took the Strained Agent
SDK, and this is important to explain why
not Bedrock agents, why not LangChain.
First of all, Bedrock agent
is configuration, yeah?
There is no code.
There is just a prompt
and just action groups.
This is not something that I wanted
to have because I saw my agent just
a construction, and this is something
that I have with the Strait agents.
And LangChain, it's about
the graphs and abstractions.
In photography, I like precision,
and maybe you already noticed
at the top the it's a vérité.
Sorry for my French . I-- and basically
it's about the truth, and truth is the
representation of the picture because…
So why I don't like stable diffusion?
Stable diffusion creates the things
that doesn't exist, and if we could
just generate a full audience with
happy people clapping to someone, then
what's the point of doing all of this?
Why we actually sit in this talk?
So then look stra-Straits,
they are mo-model driven.
Model, tool, model,
minimum frame, agent code.
It's about it was extremely
compact but extremely efficient.
Agent, tool, system prompt.
That's it.
Production deploy, I w-- u- was using
the micro VMs through the AgentCore
runtime and, so strengths actually
gives the environment where the
agent can treat every single picture
with enough honor as it deserves.
And stress trends is written-- it's pretty
much about the philosophy because we bring
the paradigm, and in this case, I also
bring my paradigm working with pictures.
And this is exactly the shift I
describe at the level of the photography
and at the level of the code.
And the agents, I have five
different positions, same
skeleton, five specialists.
You can notice the difference
on the slide, but creation and
processing, they run close on
it for the heavy judgment work.
The critic runs the same
class of the model but blind.
It sees the frame but never
the information that they have
actually operated by other agents.
What is also nice, we have the feedback.
It reads the episode log, distills what
the jury overruled, and proposed skills
and improvements for the difference.
The only agent with a pen, and I gave
it the pen that I'm normally holding.
So model, skill, tool set, everything
else, the loop and the memory rules,
the contracts, they're all identical.
This is why I can reason about the
five agents without losing my mind.
I only configure those three columns
and actually thinking about the models.
Also, I got amazing results
using Kimi K two two point
five through the marketplace.
Amazing experience using NVIDIA NeMo
Tron, and it also allowed me to close
the gap on the latency, and they are
amazing for the agentic workflows.
So this is maybe something you would
like to try through the Bedrock So
people also ask me, how did I convert
the knowledge into something that
the pipeline and the agent can use?
First of all, three pipes supply
the knowledge to the agent, and
all of them pretty much boring,
but it's done on the pur-purpose.
First of all, the, this skill is a
document, rules, examples, sources
versioned in the Git, and then it
also gets represented into the memory.
Memory allows me to save
the time on the runtime.
But every change of my craft,
this is a pull request.
Every edge case on the, from the
creation agent, also a pull request.
Basically my knowledge still
stands in the form of market
index and but also of the skills.
The golden set was not removed, but still
gives the foundation to be fortified.
But now we can define which golden
set we can actually load for, based
on my experience, and we have capable
reasoning to cover the edge cases.
For instance what I was doing to
actually supply the knowledge, first
of all, the first approach was that
I was taking different examples.
I opened Microsoft Word, enabled the
dictation, and I was sitting and saying,
"Okay, this picture my reasoning over
it is that I analyzed that, that.
I would apply those, those
corrections." And then next picture.
So mechanically, then I use local AI.
So I have one Mac Studio over here.
There is one more over here.
I have 5090 in my laptop, and I
processed so many different examples
to convert them to the skills.
And those skills, either they cover
it, the cases with which I'm working.
But I'm not perfect, actually.
I'm a very technical person.
It also finds the reflection
in the photography.
And I wanted to have some fortification
for the biases, for the special cases
where I could not agree with the others.
And here I used amazing
feature from the Kimi platform.
I used Kimi Swarm in the deep research
that time at Kimi K 2.6 model, which
is one of my all-time favorites.
And it allowed to take the best
practices with the photographer,
their approach conflicts, their
selection narratives, their
combination of a different photo sets.
So it allows me to create a amazing
automatic selections of the pictures,
and it's all based on the knowledge
of the best in the class, and it was
also prepared through by one AI agents
to another AI agents Actually, this
talk is also an example how ADLS grows
with the time, because in 2024, I have
had an issue how I would like actually
handle the representation of my golden
set, and I was trying op-open search.
I thrown it away because it was way too
much, it was too big, too expensive.
I didn't want to work with the
embeddings because I need precision.
Why do I need to summarize and
do something with a thing which
already has to be precise?
That's why I was holding k--
Lambdas cached Parquet index.
I had the custom logic to navigate
it and actually to supply the correct
examples for the editing decision.
And now everything changed.
Now my craft is baked in the S3 vectors
and S3 tables, very cheap, extremely
high performance, zero hassle for
the management, just natively can be
integrated and can be used as a tool.
What-- let's go back to
the logic of the agents.
For e-for example, let's
go back to the frame that I
presented to you in the act two.
Version one, seventy-four is
less than 80, reject silence.
Version two, the curation agent powered
by Claude actually looks at the picture.
Dark stage ex-expected at the conference.
Spotlight face readable, eyes sharp.
This is a big action moment.
Accept route to processing
with a dark stage reside.
The industry called this
culling with the system.
First pass kills technical failures.
Later passes look for the best.
My express line is a first pass,
as you remember with the mechanical
the approach in the beginning, and
the agent is everything after it.
The threshold became an argument and not a
verdict And their general approach in the
versio- version one without the agents,
Claude Haiku calls 20 similar frames, one
JSON of the parameters, hope for the best.
Yeah, and then the great pictures,
they're actually thrown away.
25,000 of the dollar per photo.
I was so proud of this number.
It was really nice, very cheap,
but this is not something
that I would like to have.
The version two with the agent,
we can now the plan the actual
corrections with the a- agent.
It develops using the Libro, but
now as a tool, measures the result,
histogram, highlight clipping,
and then keeps small adjustments.
Then it does additional iterations
kept in the step functions, and
I'm controlling the step functions,
limiting the timeouts for the agent
and also the reasoning budget.
And then the real trace comes
from the ref- from the real frame.
So the first pass 12% highlight clipping.
Then, for example, the, then
the agent pulls recovery down,
second pass, third percent down.
V1 just was guessing, V2 checks
the result that it delivers.
What is next?
Then we have a third agent,
and it's my favorite because
it fixes the silent failures.
The critic sees the final i- image
and the rubric, but never the
reasoning behind how it was made.
Blind jury like a real photo contest,
publish, rework, or escalate to a human.
This is the things it doing.
And since it jud- judges people and
the pho- photos, one honest footer
so I really forgot to mention that,
but it was agreed with the speakers.
It was p-p-processed and
then removed from the cloud.
So we are trying to take care,
and this is why we also didn't do
any custom tweaks to recognition
to recognize the specific people.
And then we have basically
a very straightforward case.
Last year, I tried to avoid the
cases to save the cost on the API.
I was analyzing the specific frames,
not the complete pictures because I
told you that I was detecting the faces,
taking the best one, and then this
face was a core for the processing.
But now, this year, I decided to
index the faces because this year
face recognition is back, but
for the important delivery job.
Because we have now four circuits
and from cheap to expensive.
And first of all, EXIF timestamp plus
the event schedule, they allow us to
understand what kind of session is it.
But this doesn't give us an understanding
what kind of session is that.
Yeah.
Then the face collection confirms,
and this then this is the
evidence with which I can work.
The caption agent also arbitrates when
they disagree, and the unknown faces
cluster as some ID, and then we can
quickly recognize the person, and agent
would, like a librarian, do the labeling
and prepare it for the sto-storaging.
For example, when we have some
conflicts or disagreements, and
schedule says Monica, but recognition
says Linda, and then it would not
be thrown to some wrong gallery.
It would be unverified and
await for our feedback.
And this is the important part because
we still keep the data and but we
don't give the agent the right to scrap
something that can be potentially reused.
I decide once in the se-- the having
the pool after the event, but we
already have enough of good pictures
that we already have covering us
and giving us this time buffer.
And basically, the unknown cluster
as a person labeled once with the ID
becomes next year training signal, and
we can have more confidence because we
have a good pool of regular speakers,
and this is like a one-time job.
Then we are just routing it co-compiling
into the speaker packages and gi-giving
them a great overview of the conference.
And actually, this resulted in a
very interesting side effect because
we built a very unique data set.
And when I was at Community Day Italy,
the-- Dario asked me like, "Can you
actually use this data to have a score
of the whole co-conference?" And I came
back home and started to think, and
probably yes, because we can analyze
how speaker felt during the session,
how people in the room felt, how was the
whole atmosphere, and how it was go-going,
but it also allows some calibration.
Yeah And I thought that maybe
I could implement it, and
here I actually implement it.
And here we have a fast caption
agent for which I either use Nova
Lite and I also tried it with
the Nemotron models from NVIDIA.
And they are doing the
writings, the emotion.
They already have the data, which is
pretty much representable, and it allows
us to use and aggregate the labels
per person and have the feeling of the
conference from different perspectives,
because we are all different.
We have different cultures,
different opinions, different
free- freedom of speech, and also
perspective on different things.
But it all was compiled in a single
pipeline that was delivering the
data to the Amazon QuickSight.
And thankfully, since we were already
operated with a good structured data,
I haven't had to do much of ETL here.
So But every frame already leaves
enough data, recognition labels, faces,
emotions, captions from the agent,
technical parameters from the camera.
It all was landing to the JSON,
to the raw zone of S3 data lake.
And then the curator agent used
partitions, used information.
Glue was used to actually
cr-crawl and create the catalogs.
Athena was taking the queries for
the dashboards, and QuickSight is
an amazing tool because you are
staying within the single ecosystem.
And as you can see, it starts from
the raw data, from the data input.
After the agency conversions,
we already have the data
input, and I just compile it.
And this leads to another
effect that I really like.
We-- not only because of the skills,
not only because of the knowledge came,
that came from me and the photographers,
we have a system that grows up based
on how much I use it and more and more,
and this is what I'm try-- as far as
you already saw, I'm trying to get the
maximum from the data I'm operating.
And this is why after the event,
I-- we were still compressing to the
golden set after the event, and my
final picks and the feedback agent
in this role compares them against
everything the system decided, writes
the lessons, the differences, the
craft rules, then I approve it by the
mechanism I told you about before.
But when there is enough material,
we distill, and we are teaching the
smaller models to act as bigger ones.
And it was a case when I was trying to
use Nova Premiere to fine-tune within
Nova Forge the Nova Light to judge
as a bigger model, saving the costs
and also improving the performance.
But most of the judgment comes in
from the reasoning of the agent.
Then going back to the case the--
about the models, because the model
strategy was important because I'm
treating them as humans, because
you notice that they have different
parameters, also different behaviors,
di-different speed capabilities, also
usage of the toolings and the judgment
jobs, curation, processing, cr-critic.
I wanted something Claude Sonnet level,
so it can be either just a Claude,
Amazon Titan Pro, it can be Kimi K 2.5.
They were pretty good doing this job.
And this is the same Claude was,
that was before at version 3.7, now
at version 5, afraid of the glasses.
This is no more, and this is a good
also incremental improvement, not from
ADL, not only from ADLS services Yeah.
And now it's hired properly.
Rekognition does the seeing, Claude
does the thinking, and this is the best
Claude is still very well capable to do.
Nova Lite is fast and cheap.
Also, Nemotron is applicable here, and
because it can prepare or, and process
all the volumes, thousands of captions
for a very fast pri- and small price.
And we have a teachers for distillation,
and it's all behind the single
Converse API, which is unified with
the who-whole AgentCore platform.
And and the best part, every model is
based in the Frankfurt region and the
whole interference was pretty close
to the processing, and that's why the
time was still very high performant.
But it was all very nice.
We got a very good quality improvement
for the things where we have, have
had the gaps or lack of lo-logics.
But still, the classic serverless
way was pretty much superior for the
express line because we could do the
fast decisions within seconds, yeah
Then as I did an example, basically,
agent is like kind of Ferrari and the
classic is more like some smaller motor
scooter or something, and everything is
good, but for the different situation.
And recognition is still good and
cheap, no idea even to replace it.
It was more about changing that we
bring it as a tool, but not just like
a set of APIs or just, some Lego.
Yes, their functions, they still
keep because they are good especially
using JSONata to keep the format
that unlocked us using the data lake.
And then we use the Rounding, all the
Apritis, Solid, Serverless foundations
to fortify to the delivery to the agents,
and where they now play the core role.
And what is actually got worse is, of
course, the latency, because models
need the reason we now have additional
processing loops, measurements, et cetera.
And it was about every stage grown
from a second to 20 seconds, si-
40, 50 seconds, depends on the case.
Costs, they blown, but it's good because
now we have a pretty much robust solution.
This is the price we are paying,
not just for to say we use AI.
We use AI to actually
make the solution better.
We lose the determinism because
there is no more just two
specific golden things here.
But basically, now there is a gap because
agents, they are always giving the
different output, despite they might have
the similar inputs, but there is still
some bias that comes from the reasoning.
But in this particular situation, it's
even good because we maintain technical
precision for the pictures, but we give
some creativity for the processing.
Yeah.
And the last one of the things and
the one of the last ones I'm proud
of, so maybe this is something that
we really haven't had last time at
Conf42, but this year I have it.
We have one frame and
full trace of action.
The creator accepts picks up this
specific parameters and analyzes the case.
For instance, like a dark stage
expectations, checks the face gestures,
positions, everything, gives the score.
Processing goes through the
iterations, and you see the numbers.
You have the logic behind shadow analysis,
leave the shadows, protect highlights
down to three, white balance correction,
and specific numbers corrected,
verified, and the critic rejects it.
There is a described motive
without of the bias because we
have the air gap between of them.
And when the sibling gets published
instead, and in case if the route
that we initially took to-- for the
analysis, then the route was taken over.
The sibling is very good correlates
with the data we produce, so we
have zero less waste that you could
have thought in the beginning.
So In version one, rejection was silence.
In the agentic approach, it's
document with the motives that gives
us a room for self-improvement.
And before I was actually set to
do it I ran it on the different
archives because I-- and I noticed
the improvement, taking aside the edge
cases varying from 80, 90% in the V1.
Agents allowed us to get almost over 95%.
To be honest, it was perfect and
it was a very great shipping gate
improvement, and not only the speaking
pictures, it also with that ones.
And what is also important, we have
had the same pictures rejudged.
I tested the calibrations, I
tested the costs, checked the
constraints, calibrated the data sets.
So use your data before you
actually go to the production.
Yeah, and looking at the prices, it's
still cheaper than the PISA because
the actual fight run, the production
run was for the conference days,
$50, which is a very great price
for the amount of work it saves.
Of course, the first play version,
it was extremely cost efficient, but
here I spent more time on actually
developing the solution for the search
of those formal that I'm sharing with
you here and rather than having it here.
So unfortunately, we are coming to the
very end and first of all, when you are
already automating some tooling, right?
Automate your judgment because,
for instance, I know some people
use AI for the security, for
DevOps, for incident response.
You give the tools, but also
you need to give the reasoning.
Please don't leave the agents
deciding because we-- there are
already so many stories about how
people just got some weird cases.
You need to supply and validate y-
the confidence that you are bringing.
Agents where the guesses were So make
sure that guess is a design error and may
let it be a fortification rather than the
issue and that you are trying to solve.
Because when you have more
guesses, agent would also make your
situation even more complicated.
Classic still stays the classic, and
please use it where it m- makes more
sense because you already have a
lot of experience with the different
automation, serverless and something.
Reuse it to best of two worlds.
You reuse it to give a base over
which as idea to build a reliable
agents, and you can win a lot
of good use cases like that one.
And even I hope you get pretty much
ins- inspired because this is not
a regular case people could work,
solve during the regular cases.
And it also proves that the flexibility
of the services, they rely on the way
how I said in the beginning, called
the opportunities, knowledge, data,
and how we look on the things we do.
And it's important to have human in the
loop in any workflow because even with
how models are clever, even we today say
that Dario says that we have to stop the
development, but honestly, Anthropic,
you still have a lot of work to do
because you should run Cloth on with
this, not with the huge data centers.
So Dario, yeah.
And you still have to have human in
the loop because the knowledge always
strikes the wall, and the wall, this is
something you have to remove, like IT
with the constant memory self-improvement.
So this talk comes after the Community
Day Dag, but please have a look on the
Community Days in your region because so
many amazing people crossing during COVID.
And there is Community Day CEE, Košice,
Romania, Poland Gdansk in Germany, in
France, in UK, in United States, also
Community Day in United Arab Emirates.
So please check the community
pages because there are so amazing
people also on the events like
Conf42 and bring your knowledge.
You can also speak out, and this is
something the case when AWS brought
the community b- fortified AWS and
AWS technology brought something
that fortified AWS community.
So if we It had, first of all,
the planning, the shooting.
If before we automated the manual
work with hands, now we automated
the soul and the way of thinking.
And this is, I hope you could also pick up
for your workflows, for your daily work.
And please add me on LinkedIn.
Please always have a ch- have
a chat, send me something.
Please also share your projects.
And also don't forget to support Conf22.
Thanks so much to Mark and to
the team for the amazing effort
doing it so many years straight.
And I hope you like the session.
Please put the comments.
I am available, and I hope we will
cross us in some real life like
it happened because Conf22 also
brought some cool people to me.
So see you somewhere, either in the
internet, either on the conference.
Best of luck to you